https://www.escapefamilysupport.org.uk/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Privacy Policy
Privacy PolicyEscape Family Support2019-03-14T18:41:23+00:00
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
BACKGROUND:
This Policy applies as between you, the User of this Website and ESCAPE Family Support Limited the owner and provider of this Website. This Policy applies to our use of any and all Data collected by us in relation to your use of the Website.
1. Definitions and Interpretation
In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:
“Data”
means collectively all information that you submit to the ESCAPE Family Support Limited via the Website. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the Data Protection Act 1998;
“Cookie”
means a small text file placed on your computer by this Website when you visit certain parts of the Website and/or when you use certain features of the Website. Details of the cookies used by this Website are set out in Clause 12;
“ESCAPE”
means ESCAPE Family Support Limited of Susan Kennedy Centre, 63 South View, Ashington, Northumberland, NE63 0SF;
“UK and EU Cookie Law”
means the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended by the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011;
“User”
means any third party that accesses the Website and is not employed by ESCAPE and acting in the course of their employment; and
“Website”
means the website that you are currently using escapefamilysupport.co.uk unless expressly excluded by their own terms and conditions.
2. Scope of this Policy
This Policy applies only to the actions of ESCAPE and Users with respect to this Website. It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Website including, but not limited to, any links we may provide to social media websites.
3. Data Collected
Without limitation, any of the following Data may be collected by this Website from time to time:
3.1
[IP address (automatically collected);]
3.2 [web browser type and version (automatically collected);]
3.3 [operating system (automatically collected);]
3.4 [a list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on this Website, and the site you exit to (automatically collected).
4. Our Use of Data
4.1 Any personal Data you submit will be retained by ESCAPE for one year.
4.2 Unless we are obliged or permitted by law to do so, and subject to Clause 5, your Data will not be disclosed to third parties. This includes our affiliates and / or other companies within our group.
4.3 All personal Data is stored securely in accordance with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998. Fore more details on security see Clause 11 below.
4.4 Any or all of the above Data may be required by us from time to time in order to provide you with the best possible service and experience when using our Website. Specifically, Data may be used by us for the following reasons:
4.4.1 [internal record keeping;]
4.4.2 [improvement of our products / services;]
5. Third Party Websites and Services
5.1 ESCAPE may, from time to time, employ the services of other parties for dealing with matters that may include, but are not limited to, payment processing, delivery of purchased items, search engine facilities, advertising and marketing. The providers of such services do not have access to certain personal Data provided by Users of this Website.
5.2 Any Data used by such parties is used only to the extent required by them to perform the services that ESCAPE requests. Any use for other purposes is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, any Data that is processed by third parties shall be processed within the terms of this Policy and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.
6. Links to Other Websites
This Website may, from time to time, provide links to other websites. ESCAPE has no control over such websites and is in no way responsible for the content thereof. This Policy does not extend to your use of such websites. Users are advised to read the privacy policy or statement of other websites prior to using them.
7.Changes of Business Ownership and Control
7.1 ESCAPE may, from time to time, expand or reduce our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of ESCAPE. Data provided by Users will, where it is relevant to any part of our business so transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was originally supplied to us.
7.2 In the event that any Data submitted by Users is to be transferred in such a manner, you will be contacted in advance and informed of the changes. When contacted you be given the choice to have your Data deleted or withheld from the new owner or controller.
8. Security
Data security is of great importance to ESCAPE and to protect your Data we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure Data collected via this Website.
9. Cookies
9.1 This Website may place and access certain first party Cookies on your computer. First party cookies are those placed directly by ESCAPE via this Website and are used only by ESCAPE. ESCAPE uses Cookies to improve your experience of using the Website and to improve our range of services. ESCAPE has carefully chosen these Cookies and has taken steps to ensure that your privacy is protected and respected at all times.
9.2 By using this Website you may receive certain third party Cookies on your computer. Third party cookies are those placed by websites and/or parties other than ESCAPE. Third party cookies are used on this Website for analytics and are detailed in full below. These cookies are not integral to the services provided by the Website.
9.3 All Cookies used by this Website are used in accordance with current UK and EU Cookie Law.
9.4 Before Cookies are placed on your computer, you will be presented with a message bar requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling ESCAPE to provide the best possible experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of the Website may not function fully or as intended.
9.5 The following third party Cookies may be placed on your computer:
Name of Cookie
Provider
Purpose
analytics.js
Google
Tracking visits and user preferences to the website.
9.6 This Website uses analytics services provided by Google. Website analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse usage statistics, enabling us to better understand how Users use the Website. This, in turn, enables us to improve the Website and the services offered through it. You do not have to allow us to use these Cookies, as detailed below, however whilst our use of them does not pose any risk to your privacy or your safe use of the Website, it does enable us to continually improve our business.
9.7 The analytics services used by this Website use Cookies to gather the required information. Certain of these Cookies may be placed immediately when you decide to visit the Website and it may not be possible to obtain your prior consent. You may remove these Cookies and prevent future use of them by following the steps set out below.
9.8 The analytics services used by this Website use the following Cookies:
Name of Cookie
First / Third Party
Provider
Purpose
analytics.js
Third Party
Google
Tracking visits and user preferences to the website.
9.9 You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. Most internet browsers also enable you to choose whether you wish to disable all cookies or only third party cookies. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser.
9.10 You can choose to delete Cookies at any time however you may lose any information that enables you to access the Website more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, personalisation settings.
9.11 It is recommended that you ensure that your internet browser is up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.
Changes to this Policy
ESCAPE reserves the right to change this Policy as we may deem necessary from time to time or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the Website and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the Policy on your first use of the Website following the alterations.
Go to Top
